Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. James Freeman Clarke additional papers, 1717-1889 (MS Am 1569.1): Guide.
James Freeman Clarke additional papers,
- IV. Scrapbooks, journals, sketchbooks, financial records and other papers of James Freeman Clarke
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Journal: autograph manuscript, circa 1838-1844., (151); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    - Inside front cover
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Scrapbook of pictures and drawings, circa 1835-1840., (152); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Includes prints, watercolor drawings, graphite sketches, maps, clippings, and other material.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (11).
    - Profile drawing of "SMF."
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888, compiler. The letters of a sister (Sarah F. Clarke 1831-1840): clippings in a scrapbook, 1831-1840., (153); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Letters are to James Freeman Clarke.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (12).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Auto-Biography. J.F.C. or thoughts & events out of my life: autograph manuscript, undated., (154); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (13).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Journal of a voyage & stay in Europe 1849: autograph manuscript, 1849., (155); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Includes text and sketches.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (15).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Journal: autograph manuscript, 1850-1851., (156); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (16).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Album of poems: autograph manuscript, undated., (157); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Includes poems, sketches, translations, and other material.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (17).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Autobiographical annals from my diaries. Topics for the autobiography: autograph manuscript, 1851-1852., (158); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    "Memoranda about a trip to Washington in 1851 and a journey in Europe in 1852."
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (18).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Journal: autograph manuscript, clippings,1866-1883., (159); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Includes text, clippings, notices, lists, quotations, etc ...
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (19).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. General account book: autograph manuscript, 1859-1860., (160); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (20).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. Expense books: autograph manuscript, 1846, 1849 and 1855., (161); 3 volumes in 3 folders.
    3 items.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (21).
  - Clarke, James Freeman, 1810-1888. President Cleveland and his administration: clippings, autograph manuscript fragments, 1887., (162); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (23).
  - James Freeman Clarke: etching, lithograph, photomechanical print, undated., (163); 1 folders
    1 image (with multiple copies) etching, by A. H. Ritchie; 1 image (2 copies) lithograph; and 1 image photomechanical print.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (25).
  - James Freeman Clarke reading a book: photograph, undated., (164); 1 folders
- V. Family papers
  These items were moved out of the earlier series.
  - Family letters: manuscript, 1717-1845., (165); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Letters are mounted in scrapbook. With a manuscript list of names.
    Includes the following correspondents: 1 of Joseph May?, 17 of James Freeman, 1 of George Tickner, 11 of William Hull, 1 of Isaac Hull, 3 of Maria Hull, 4 of Ann Hull, 2 of Rebecca Hull Clarke, 3 of Martha Curtis Clarke Freeman, 2 of "Pastors", and 1 of J. Buckminster.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (26).
  - Clarke, Cora H. (Cora Huidekoper), 1851-1916, compiler. European trip 1882 - Cora Clarke: scrapbook of photographs, 1882., (166)
    Includes loose images and an autograph manuscript partial index to photographs.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (14).
  - Clarke, Lillian Freeman, 1842-1921. Diaries: autograph manuscript, 1881, 1883, 1885, 1888, and 1889., (167); 5 volumes in 1 folder.
    Includes card of pressed flowers/leaves tucked into pocket of one diary.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (22).
  - Dall, Caroline Wells Healey, 1822-1912. Studies towards the life of a "business woman" being conversations with Mrs. R. P. Clarke in the winter of 1864-1865: manuscript transcript (in the hand of James Freeman Clarke), 1865 February., (168); 3 volumes in 3 folders.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (24).
  - Fuller, Timothy, 1778-1835. Letter book: manuscript, 1806-1828., (169); 1 volume in 1 folder.
    Formerly MS Am 1569.3 (11a).